<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on CovData Shorts</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on CovData Shorts</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <managingEditor>covanalytics@covingtonky.gov?subject=CovData%20Short%20Idea</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>covanalytics@covingtonky.gov?subject=CovData%20Short%20Idea</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>CovConnect Data Trends</title>
      <link>/post/2023-03-13-covconnect-data-trends/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>covanalytics@covingtonky.gov?subject=CovData%20Short%20Idea</author>
      <guid>/post/2023-03-13-covconnect-data-trends/</guid>
      <description>Covington Connect is an aggressive effort to smash the digital divide in Covington by expanding access to free public Wi-Fi throughout much of the City.
In a previous post, we outlined the purpose, partners, and phases of the Covington Connect project. This post briefly looks at the data trends of Wi-Fi users, specifically how much data has been downloaded and uploaded by student and non-student users since December 2020.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>U.S. Recessions and Covington</title>
      <link>/post/2023-02-07-u-s-recessions-and-covington/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>covanalytics@covingtonky.gov?subject=CovData%20Short%20Idea</author>
      <guid>/post/2023-02-07-u-s-recessions-and-covington/</guid>
      <description>There have been four economic recessions in the United States since the early 1990s. A recession is a significant, widespread, and prolonged downturn in economic activity, and is typically identified by two consecutive quarters of negative gross domestic product (GDP) growth.1 One of the most noticeable effects of a recession is a rise in unemployment, which usually peaks long after the recession has begun and can last well into recovery.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Special Event Permits</title>
      <link>/post/2023-01-05-special-event-permits/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>covanalytics@covingtonky.gov?subject=CovData%20Short%20Idea</author>
      <guid>/post/2023-01-05-special-event-permits/</guid>
      <description>Any event (i.e. festival, concert, run/walk, art show, etc.) that uses, or will likely have a large impact on public or City-owned property, such as streets or parks, requires a Special Event Permit Application. This is information that the City of Covington requires to ensure that everything goes smoothly and safely with the event.
Some events, naturally, last longer than others. What kind of world would this be if we only have one day to enjoy the Rockin Taco Fest?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Current Revenues and Expenses</title>
      <link>/post/2022-12-09-current-revenues-and-expenses/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>covanalytics@covingtonky.gov?subject=CovData%20Short%20Idea</author>
      <guid>/post/2022-12-09-current-revenues-and-expenses/</guid>
      <description>Each year, the City of Covington is required by State law to publish an Annual Comprehensive Financial Report (ACFR) in cooperation with an independent firm of licensed certified public accounts. The ACFR is intended to provide informative and relevant financial data to the residents of the City, the City Commission, investors, creditors and any other interested reader. It includes all statements and disclosures necessary for the reader to obtain a thorough understanding of the City’s financial activities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Solar Panel Installations</title>
      <link>/post/2022-10-31-solar-panel-installations/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>covanalytics@covingtonky.gov?subject=CovData%20Short%20Idea</author>
      <guid>/post/2022-10-31-solar-panel-installations/</guid>
      <description>The Planning and Development Services of Kenton County (PDS) provides the City of Covington with data containing details on every building permit issued in Covington, including the type of work planned for a property and how much the work is expected to cost. Figure 1 shows that the installation of solar panels is a particular property enhancement that has become increasingly popular in recent years. In the last two years alone, interest in solar panels has jumped considerably, with owners of 74 properties in Covington completing the necessary paperwork to have solar panels installed—work valued at an estimated $1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>City Website Traffic</title>
      <link>/post/2022-09-28-city-website-traffic/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>covanalytics@covingtonky.gov?subject=CovData%20Short%20Idea</author>
      <guid>/post/2022-09-28-city-website-traffic/</guid>
      <description>The website for the City of Covington is visited by people from all over the United States, and world. With the help of Google Analytics, the City is able to monitor all of the website pages and gain insights into visitor activity, such as the number of visitors, most viewed pages, device types, and much more.
In Figure 1, for example, we can see where returning visits to the City of Covington website on a mobile device originated by state and city in the last 100 days.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Taxable Property Additions</title>
      <link>/post/2022-09-07-taxable-property-additions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>covanalytics@covingtonky.gov?subject=CovData%20Short%20Idea</author>
      <guid>/post/2022-09-07-taxable-property-additions/</guid>
      <description>Each year the City of Covington receives a tax assessment report from the Kenton County Property Value Administrator that determines the taxable value of real property in the City, specifically for the purpose of levying and collecting tax money that is used to support the community. Included in the report is a record of taxable additions to property. The additions, basically, represent economic investment through the development of new property or through the enhancement of existing property.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CovConnect Registrations</title>
      <link>/post/2022-08-22-covconnect-registrations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>covanalytics@covingtonky.gov?subject=CovData%20Short%20Idea</author>
      <guid>/post/2022-08-22-covconnect-registrations/</guid>
      <description>Covington Connect is an aggressive effort to smash the digital divide in Covington by expanding access to free public Wi-Fi throughout much of the City.
Covington Connect is a collaborative effort involving the City of Covington, Cincinnati Bell, the Housing Authority of Covington (HAC), Covington Independent Public Schools, Renaissance Covington, local computer firms Blair Technology Group and ReGadget, and Comp-U-Dopt, a Houston-based non-profit organization.
Phase I of the project began in 2018 with setting up 22 Wi-Fi hotspots that created zones of connectivity in the downtown area.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
