<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Development on CovData Shorts</title>
    <link>/tags/development/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Development on CovData Shorts</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <managingEditor>covanalytics@covingtonky.gov?subject=CovData%20Short%20Idea</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>covanalytics@covingtonky.gov?subject=CovData%20Short%20Idea</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/development/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>In the Cov, employees steadily returning to the office</title>
      <link>/post/2025-03-05-in-the-cov-employees-steadily-returning-to-the-office/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>covanalytics@covingtonky.gov?subject=CovData%20Short%20Idea</author>
      <guid>/post/2025-03-05-in-the-cov-employees-steadily-returning-to-the-office/</guid>
      <description>During the onset of the Covid-19 pandemic in 2020, many workplaces utilized work-from-home strategies as a way to protect employees from an infectious virus about which little was known.
In the immediate years since, the work-from-home philosophy lingered. Little by little, however, at least in Covington, the number of employees in the workplace continue to rise, though not yet to pre-pandemic levels.
The chart above shows the year-by-year average of daily foot traffic from Placer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>191% increase in women with PhDs</title>
      <link>/post/2025-01-28-191-increase-in-women-with-phds/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>covanalytics@covingtonky.gov?subject=CovData%20Short%20Idea</author>
      <guid>/post/2025-01-28-191-increase-in-women-with-phds/</guid>
      <description>Along with increases in household income in The Cov over the last few years have come similar improvements in post-secondary educational attainment.
For example, between 2009 and 2023, the percent of Covington residents age 25 and older who have earned at least an associate’s degree from a college or university increased from 22 percent to 32 percent, according the American Community Survey.
Drill down even further and you find this interesting fact, as shown in the accompanying chart: The number of women living in Covington with doctoral degrees increased from 59 in 2021 to 172 in 2023.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BLINK foot traffic more than doubled &#39;24 high</title>
      <link>/post/2024-10-25-blink-foot-traffic-more-than-doubled-24-high/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>covanalytics@covingtonky.gov?subject=CovData%20Short%20Idea</author>
      <guid>/post/2024-10-25-blink-foot-traffic-more-than-doubled-24-high/</guid>
      <description>If downtown Covington seemed crowded last weekend during the four-day BLINK outdoor light and art event, it was. Very crowded. Especially compared to every other evening of 2024.
This chart shows peak foot traffic night by night during the event, as compared to every other evening in 2024, in the area where the BLINK installations were featured. The peak night – Saturday – is more than double the two previous highs during the year, which we think came during St.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grants for urgent home repairs keep vulnerable Covington families in their homes</title>
      <link>/post/2024-09-27-grants-for-urgent-home-repairs-keep-vulenrable-families-in-their-homes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>covanalytics@covingtonky.gov?subject=CovData%20Short%20Idea</author>
      <guid>/post/2024-09-27-grants-for-urgent-home-repairs-keep-vulenrable-families-in-their-homes/</guid>
      <description>More than 130 times in the last 10 years, the City of Covington has helped vulnerable low-income homeowners – including the elderly, veterans, and those with disabilities – fix dangerous and unsafe conditions that could drive them from their homes.
In its current setup, the federally funded Homeowner Repair Program offers grants of up to $10,000 to fix owner-occupied, single-family homes in any area of Covington.
Eligible repairs include certain electrical problems, plumbing issues (including broken water heaters and leaking pipes), HVAC problems (including carbon monoxide leaks and malfunctioning AC units/furnaces), roofs (plus gutters and downspouts), and accessibility modifications (like wheelchair ramps and handrails).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grants Helped 14 Neighborhoods</title>
      <link>/post/2024-09-16-grants-helped-14-neighborhoods/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>covanalytics@covingtonky.gov?subject=CovData%20Short%20Idea</author>
      <guid>/post/2024-09-16-grants-helped-14-neighborhoods/</guid>
      <description>When neighborhoods have a plan and the desire to improve their communities, they turn to the City for financial help.
Covington leaders created the Neighborhood Grant Program in 2019 to enhance the physical appearance of small areas while enhancing the sense of social cohesion through shared projects.
Since then, the City has distributed about $170,000 for 37 projects in at least 14 neighborhoods (plus a cemetery/arboretum), including things like tree planting, flower pots, banners, dog-waste stations, festivals, water fountains, signs and benches.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Revenue &#39;Furnace&#39;</title>
      <link>/post/2024-08-16-revenue-furnace/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>covanalytics@covingtonky.gov?subject=CovData%20Short%20Idea</author>
      <guid>/post/2024-08-16-revenue-furnace/</guid>
      <description>Just under 60 percent of the tax revenue generated in Covington for the City’s General Fund comes from occupational license revenue (which includes both the payroll tax and net profit tax).
The General Fund is the operations fund used to pay the salaries of employees who deliver most City services – such as Police, EMS, Fire, Public Works, and Parks &amp;amp; Rec.
This heat map shows where that revenue was generated in calendar year 2023.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Homebuyer Assistance</title>
      <link>/post/2024-07-31-homebuyer-assistance/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>covanalytics@covingtonky.gov?subject=CovData%20Short%20Idea</author>
      <guid>/post/2024-07-31-homebuyer-assistance/</guid>
      <description>In the last 10 years, the City of Covington has helped 426 families buy a home in The Cov by offering help with down payments and closing costs.
The best part? The loans are forgiven a little each year the families stay in their house.
The attached chart and map show how the loans have been spread across Covington’s residential neighborhoods. For example, there were 187 in Latonia’s four areas, 42 in South Covington, 68 in Peaselburg, and 21 in Eastside.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Home Sales in the Cov</title>
      <link>/post/2024-07-30-home-sales-in-the-cov/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>covanalytics@covingtonky.gov?subject=CovData%20Short%20Idea</author>
      <guid>/post/2024-07-30-home-sales-in-the-cov/</guid>
      <description>What does a house cost in The Cov?
Depends (greatly) on where you look.
With the affordability of housing a frequent topic of conversation these days, the City of Covington’s analytics manager took a dive into 2023 sales by neighborhood and found a wide range of prices, with a few outliers.
The median sales price in 13 of the 23 neighborhoods was less than $200,000. In seven neighborhoods, it was $161,000 or less.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Covington Median Household Income</title>
      <link>/post/2024-03-18-covington-median-household-income-2009-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>covanalytics@covingtonky.gov?subject=CovData%20Short%20Idea</author>
      <guid>/post/2024-03-18-covington-median-household-income-2009-2022/</guid>
      <description>The median household income in Covington in 2009 was $38,700. By 2022, that number had grown to $53,800 – an increase of $15,100. Other Kentucky cities of similar size – such as Bowling Green, Elizabethtown, Hopkinsville, Owensboro, and Richmond – showed similar growth in that 13-year period, according to data from the American Community Survey (ACS) from the U.S. Census Bureau.
Why is this important? Household income not only improves an individual family’s buying power but is also considered a valuable measure of the relative economic well-being of a city.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Where Do Covington Workers Live?</title>
      <link>/post/2023-06-30-where-do-covington-workers-live/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>covanalytics@covingtonky.gov?subject=CovData%20Short%20Idea</author>
      <guid>/post/2023-06-30-where-do-covington-workers-live/</guid>
      <description>In a previous post we briefly looked at where Covington residents work within the Cincinnati-Wilmington-Maysville Combined Statistical Area (CSA) using the most recent LEHD Origin-Destination Employment Statistics (LODES) dataset for the year 2020. The dataset links home and work locations at the census block-level, making it easy to answer questions about where people work and where workers live.
In this post, we look briefly at where people working in Covington live within the Cincinnati-Wilmington-Maysville CSA.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Where Do Covington Residents Work?</title>
      <link>/post/2023-05-23-where-do-covington-residents-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>covanalytics@covingtonky.gov?subject=CovData%20Short%20Idea</author>
      <guid>/post/2023-05-23-where-do-covington-residents-work/</guid>
      <description>The Longitudinal Employer-Household Dynamics (LEHD) program is part of the Center for Economic Studies at the U.S. Census Bureau. The LEHD program produces cost effective, public-use information combining federal, state and Census Bureau data on employers and employees under the Local Employment Dynamics (LED) Partnership. State and local authorities increasingly need detailed local information about their economies to make informed decisions. The LED Partnership works to fill critical data gaps and provide indicators needed by state and local authorities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>U.S. Recessions and Covington</title>
      <link>/post/2023-02-07-u-s-recessions-and-covington/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>covanalytics@covingtonky.gov?subject=CovData%20Short%20Idea</author>
      <guid>/post/2023-02-07-u-s-recessions-and-covington/</guid>
      <description>There have been four economic recessions in the United States since the early 1990s. A recession is a significant, widespread, and prolonged downturn in economic activity, and is typically identified by two consecutive quarters of negative gross domestic product (GDP) growth.1 One of the most noticeable effects of a recession is a rise in unemployment, which usually peaks long after the recession has begun and can last well into recovery.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Solar Panel Installations</title>
      <link>/post/2022-10-31-solar-panel-installations/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>covanalytics@covingtonky.gov?subject=CovData%20Short%20Idea</author>
      <guid>/post/2022-10-31-solar-panel-installations/</guid>
      <description>The Planning and Development Services of Kenton County (PDS) provides the City of Covington with data containing details on every building permit issued in Covington, including the type of work planned for a property and how much the work is expected to cost. Figure 1 shows that the installation of solar panels is a particular property enhancement that has become increasingly popular in recent years. In the last two years alone, interest in solar panels has jumped considerably, with owners of 74 properties in Covington completing the necessary paperwork to have solar panels installed—work valued at an estimated $1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Taxable Property Additions</title>
      <link>/post/2022-09-07-taxable-property-additions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>covanalytics@covingtonky.gov?subject=CovData%20Short%20Idea</author>
      <guid>/post/2022-09-07-taxable-property-additions/</guid>
      <description>Each year the City of Covington receives a tax assessment report from the Kenton County Property Value Administrator that determines the taxable value of real property in the City, specifically for the purpose of levying and collecting tax money that is used to support the community. Included in the report is a record of taxable additions to property. The additions, basically, represent economic investment through the development of new property or through the enhancement of existing property.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
